Guide to the William A. Speck Collection of Prints
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Portraits, Series I; 5; (12 boxes)
  - "W"
    - Walch, Frau Christine Friederike Wilhelmine Herzlieb, 1789-1865 (Box 11, Folder +)
    - Walderdorf, Johann Philipp von (Johann IX, Elector of Trier), 1701-1768 (Box 11, Folder +)
    - Wallraf, Ferdinand Franz, 1748-1824 (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Wedel, Otto Joachim Moritz von, 1752-1794 (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Weisse, Christian Felix, 1726-1804 (Box 12, Folder ++)
    - Wenzel, Christine (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Werner, Zacharias, 1768-1823 (Box 12, Folder ++)
    - Werthern-Beichlingen, Johanna Luise Gräfin von Freiin vom und zum Stein, 1752-1811 (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Wieland, Christoph Martin, 1733-1813 (Box 12, Folder ++)
    - Wieland - Family (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Willemer, Johann Jakob, 1760-1838 (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Willemer, Frau Marianne Jung von, 1784-1860 (Box 12, Folder ++)
    - Winckelmann, Johann Joachim, 1717-1768 (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Winkler, Gottfried, 1731-1795 (Box 12, Folder ++)
    - Winterberger, Georg Friedrich, 1804-1860 (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Witthoeft (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Wolf, E. W. (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Wolf, Friedrich August, 1759-1824 (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Wolff, Frau Anna Amalia Christiane Malcolmi Becker, 1783-1851 (Box 12, Folder ++)
    - Wolff, Pius Alexander, 1782-1828 (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Wolowska, Casimira (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Wolzogen - Family (Box 12, Folder +)
  - "Z"
    - Zachariae, Justus Friedrich Wilhelm, 1726-1777 (Box 12, Folder ++)
    - Zelter, Dorothea Augusta Cäcilia, 1792-1852 (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Zelter, Karl Friedrich, 1758-1832 (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Zimmermann, Johann Georg, Ritter von, 1728-1795 (Box 12, Folder +)
    - Zumsteeg, Johann Rudolf (Box 12, Folder ++)
    - Unidentified (Box 12, Folder +)
- Views, Series II; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  Series II, Views is arranged alphabetically by country, and then by city. The names reflect names of countries and cities which may be now obsolete.
  - AUSTRIA
    - Unidentified (Box 13, Folder +)
    - Bozen (Box 13, Folder +)
  - CZECHOSLOVAKIA
    - Bilin (Box 13, Folder +)
    - Elbogen (Box 13, Folder +)
    - Eger (Box 13, Folder ++)
    - Eger - Surroundings (Box 13, Folder +)
    - Franzensbad (Box 13, Folder ++)
    - Karlsbad (Box 13, Folder ++)
    - Marienbad (Box 13, Folder ++)
    - Tepl (Box 13, Folder +)
    - Teplitz (Box 13, Folder ++)
    - Triblitz (Box 13, Folder +)
    - Miscellaneous - Costumes (Box 13, Folder +)
    - Miscellaneous - Customs (Box 13, Folder +)
  - FRANCE
    - Strasbourg (Box 14, Folder +++)
    - Longwy (Box 14, Folder +)
  - GERMANY
    - Altdorf (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Altenau (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Altenberg (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Sanct Andreasberg (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Artern (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Astmanshausen (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Augsburg (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Ballenstedt (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Berka (Box 14, Folder ++)
    - Biebrich (Box 14, Folder ++)
    - Bingen - Rochuskapelle (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Bingen (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Blankenburg (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Bonn (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Bornheim (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Buchsweiler (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Clausthal (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Darmstadt (Box 14, Folder ++)
    - Dessau (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Dornburg (Box 14, Folder ++)
    - Drakendorf (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Dresden (Box 14, Folder ++)
    - Düsseldorf (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Ehrenbreitstein (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Eisenach (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Eisenach - Wartburg (Box 14, Folder ++)
    - Eisenach - Wilhelmsthal (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Elberfeld (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Emmendingen (Box 14, Folder +)
    - Ems (Box 14, Folder ++)
    - Erfurt (Box 14, Folder ++)
    - Frankfurt
      - Complete Views, etc. (Box 14, Folder +)
      - General Views (Box 14, Folder +)
      - Separate Scenes & Streets (Box 14, Folder +)
      - Gerbermühle (Box 14, Folder +)
      - Views from River Bank (Box 14, Folder ++)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder +)
      - Goethehaus (Box 14, Folder ++)
      - Goethehaus - Inneres (Box 14, Folder +)
      - Churches (Box 15, Folder ++)
      - Römer (Box 15, Folder +)
      - Senckenbergische (Box 15, Folder +)
      - Weidenhof (Box 15, Folder +)
      - Willemer Häuscher (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Garbenheim (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Giebichenstien (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Göttingen (Box 15, Folder ++)
    - Goslar (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Gotha (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Giessen (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Halberstadt (Box 15, Folder ++)
    - Hamburg (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Harz (Box 15, Folder ++)
    - Heidelberg (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Heilbronn (Box 15, Folder ++)
    - Hessen (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Hirschberg (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Höchst (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Hohenheim (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Ilfeld (Box 15, Folder ++)
    - Ilmenau (Box 15, Folder ++)
    - Ilmenau - Gabelbach (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Ilmenau - Kickelhann (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Jagsthausen (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Jena - City (Box 15, Folder ++)
    - Jena - Surroundings (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Johannisberg (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Karlsruhe (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Kassel (Box 15, Folder ++)
    - Klausthal (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Knittlingen (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Koblenz (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Kochberg (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Köln (Box 15, Folder ++)
    - Langensalza (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Lauchstädt (Box 15, Folder ++)
    - Lauchstädt - Theatre (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Leipzig (Box 15, Folder ++)
    - Leipzig - Keller & Höfe (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Leipzig - Surroundings (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Lobeda (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Löbstedt (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Ludwigsburg (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Mainz (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Mannheim (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Maulbronn (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Meissenheim (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Mittenwald (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Nassau (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Neuburg (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Neuwied (Box 15, Folder +)
    - Niederrödern (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Nürnberg (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Oberrossla (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Odilienberg (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Offenbach (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Ossmannstedt (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Oybin (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Pössneck (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Pyrmont (Box 16, Folder ++)
    - Regensburg (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Rhein (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Rudolstadt (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Rüdesheim (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Ruhla (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Sesenheim (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Sesenheim - Kirche (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Stuttgart (Box 16, Folder ++)
    - Sulzbach an der Saar (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Unidentified (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Vallendar (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Volpertshausen (Box 16, Folder +)
    - Weimar
      - General scenes (Box 16, Folder +)
      - Separate Scenes, Streets (Box 16, Folder +)
      - Churches, Cemeteries (Box 16, Folder +)
      - Kassengewölbe (Box 16, Folder +)
      - Goethes Haus (Box 16, Folder +)
      - Goethes Garten (Box 16, Folder +)
      - Goethes Gartenhaus (Box 16, Folder +)
      - Goethes Haus - Inneres (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Bibliothek (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Tempelherrenhaus (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Theater (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Bertuchs Haus (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Herders Haus (Box 17, Folder ++)
      - Lassbergs Haus (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Residenz Schloss (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Steins Haus (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Wilhelmsburg (Box 17, Folder ++)
      - Wittumspalais (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Parks, Squares, Monuments (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Park - Römisches Haus (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Park - Stern (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Schillers Haus (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Stützerbach (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Celebrations, etc., 1816 (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Celebrations, 1825 (Box 17, Folder +)
      - 1932 - March Goethe Celebrations (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Surroundings - Belvedere (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Surroundings - Ettersburg (Box 17, Folder +)
      - Surroundings - Tiefurt (Box 17, Folder +)
    - Wernigerode (Box 17, Folder +)
    - Wetzlar (Box 17, Folder ++)
    - Wiesbaden (Box 17, Folder ++)
    - Wilhelmsbad (Box 17, Folder +)
    - Winkel (Box 17, Folder +)
    - Wörlitz (Box 17, Folder +)
    - Zabern (Box 17, Folder +)
    - Zellerfeld (Box 17, Folder +)
  - ITALY
    - General Views (Box 17, Folder +)
    - Albano - Lago d'Albano (Box 17, Folder +)
    - Caserta (Box 17, Folder +)
    - Castel Gandolfo (Box 17, Folder +)
    - Frascati (Box 18, Folder ++)
    - Girgenti (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Malcesine (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Napoli (Box 18, Folder ++)
    - Padova (Box 18, Folder ++)
    - Palermo (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Pompei (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Pozzuoli (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Roma (Box 18, Folder ++)
    - Roma - Paintings & Sculptures (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Segesta (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Sicilia (Box 18, Folder ++)
    - Sorrento (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Taormina (Box 18, Folder ++)
    - Torbole (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Trieste (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Venezia (Box 18, Folder ++)
    - Verona (Box 18, Folder ++)
  - SWITZERLAND
    - General Views (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Altorf (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Einsiedeln (Box 18, Folder ++)
    - Fluelen (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Gotthard (Sankt Gotthard) (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Grindelwald (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Küssnacht (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Rigi (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Schindellegi (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Schwanau (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Schwyz (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Sihlwald (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Stäfa (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Stans (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Staubbach (Box 18, Folder +)
    - Zürich (Box 18, Folder ++)
    - Leuker Bad (Box 18, Folder +)
  - UNIDENTIFIED
    - Unidentified (Box 18, Folder +)
- Illustrations, Series III; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series III, Illustrations, is arranged into three subseries, Faust, Goethe's Other Works, and Miscellaneous.
  - FAUST
    - Miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder +)
    - Scenes
      - Nacht. Offen Feld (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Strasse (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Prolog (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Studierzimmer (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Walpurgisnacht (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Wald und Hoehle (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Strasse vor Gretchens tuer (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Osterspaziergang (Box 19, Folder +)
    - Illustrations
      - Auerbachs Keller (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Dom (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Garten (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Gretchen am Brunnen (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Gretchens Stube (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Hexenkueche (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Kerker (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Mater Dolorosa (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Mater Dolorosa (pencil sketch) (Box 19, Folder +)
    - Characters
      - Faust, Johann (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Valentine (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Mephistopheles (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Erdgeist (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Gretchen (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Faust's House - Prag. (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Fust, the printer who is sometimes confused with the legendary character. Fust, Johann, ca. 1400-1466 (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Faust im Bischofskeller zu Salzburg (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Faust's Geburtshaus in Roda (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Wagner (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Schueler (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Homunculus (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Marthe (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Faust (Box 19, Folder +)
    - Artists
      - Unidentified watercolors (Box 19, Folder +)
      - van Bergen (Original Aquar.) (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Brekelenkamp [?] 1663 (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Burgdorfer. (Orig. Federzeichnung mit Sepia. "Gretchen im Zwinger vor der Mater Dolorosa." (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Champollion, E. (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Delacroix (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Diethe, Alfred Richard (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Duschek, R. (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Kaulbach (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Kreling (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Kretzschmar (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Liebermann, Ernst (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Liezen Meyer (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Lyser, Johann Peter. Mephistopheles. Ein polltisch-satyr. Taschenbuch... 1833. Leipzig (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Makart, Hans (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Muhr (Kaffeklexbilder) (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Naeke - Strixner (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Nehrlich (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Pecht (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Rabe, Robert (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Radziwill (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Ramberg (Box 19, Folder +)
      - Rembrandt (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Retzsch (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Rhode (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Scheffer, Ary (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Schiching (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Schlick (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Schnorr, L. Th. (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Seibertz (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Slevogt (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Stichart, R. "Gretchens Kirchgang" ca. 1890. Original (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Twardowski (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Ward. Set of prints from 6 wood blocks engraved & signed by Lynd Ward (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Unidentified (Box 20, Folder +)
    - Related Material
      - Klinger, Friedrich Maximillan von - Faust's Laben Thaten und Höllenfahrt (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Lenau, Nicolaus, Edler von Strehlenau (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Postal Cards with Quotations (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Theater Guild 1928, New York City (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Repr. of title-pages, theatre bills, & other printed material (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Stage Production - Dornach (Switzerland) (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Stage Production - Tokio (Japan) (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Music - Miscellaneous covers from sheet music (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Mephistofele - Boito's Opera (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Puzzle (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Robert Der Teufel (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Merlin (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Faustsplitter (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Faustsage. Im Rathaus zu Erfurt. Ed. Kaempffer (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Neuss - 1932 Rhein. Städtebundtheater (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Stage productions (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Silhouettes (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Silhouettes - [Robert] Erbe. Original Silhouettes to Goethes Faust I by Robert Erbe. Dresden, 1901 (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Quotations illustrated (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Medal (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Miscellaneous chap-books (covers) (Box 20, Folder +)
      - Der Ewige Jude (Box 20, Folder +)
  - GOETHE'S OTHER WORKS
    - Miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder +)
    - C. & W. Kaulbach, Pecht, Bendel & Muttenthaler. Engr. by various artists (Box 20, Folder +)
    - Ahasver (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Die Bekehrte - Ramberg - Stölzel (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Die Braut von Corinth - Kaulbach Enzing-Müller (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Der Bürgergeneral - Kaulbach - Spiess (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Dichtung und Wahrheit (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Egmont
      - Kaulbach - Merz, Fr. Weber (Box 21, Folder +)
      - Pecht - Geyer (Box 21, Folder +)
      - Ramberg - Axmann, Jury, Schwerdgeburth (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Elegien (F.J.H. Drake: Goethe's Fifth Roman Elegy) (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Erlkönig (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Der Fischer. Kaulbach - Steifensand (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Der Fischer. Voltz - Nussbiegel (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Don Juan and Faust (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Dis Geschwister - Ramberg - Axmann (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Götz von Berlichingen - Stilke - Steifensansd (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Götz von Berlichingen - Ramberg - Böhm, Jury, Stölzel jun., etc. (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Heidenröslein (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Heidenröslein - Ramberg - Jaquemot (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Hermann und Dorothea - Ramberg - Romney (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Hermann und Dorothea (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Iphigenie (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Iphigenie - Ramberg - Axmann, Jury, Schwerdgeburth (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Iphigenie - Neuss - 1932 (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Iphigenie - Stage Productions - Berca, Ohio (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Jery & Bätely - Ramberg - Schwerdgeburth (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Künstlers Erdenwallen - Bendel - Schleich (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Die Laune des Verliebten. Bristol, Vermont, 1932. German School, Middlebury College (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Der Müllerin Verrath - Ramberg - Jury (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Der Müllerin Reue - Ramberg - Böhm (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Der neue Amor - Ramberg - Böhm (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Paläophron & Neoterpe (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Prometheus - v. Muyden - Gonzenbach (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Reynard the Fox (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Reineke Fuchs - Kaulbach - Jaquemot (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Der Schatzgräber - Ramberg - Stölzel (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Tancred (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Torquato Tasso - Dejuinne - Buser (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Torquato Tasso - P. C. Geissler - Axmann, Buser, Fleischmann, Schwerdgeburth, Wagner (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Torquato Tasso - Naecke - H. Meyer (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Torquato Tasso - van Muyden - Schad (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Uber Kunst und Altherthum (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Die Wahlverwandtschaften - Muttenthaler - F. Weber (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Werther - Miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder ++)
    - Werther - Bendel - Steifensand (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Werther - Chodowiecke - Berger (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Werther - Chodowiecke - Copia (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Werther - Chodowiecke - Geyser - Johannot (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Werther - Lalauze (Box 21, Folder ++)
    - Werther - Moreau - Simonet (2), Ghendt (1) (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Werther - Ramberg - Döbler, Beyer, Wagner, Rossmässler, Buser, Walther, Axmann (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Werther - Ramberg - Zancon (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Werther - Satirical picture - Sayer (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Wilhelm Meisters Lehrjahre - Kaulbach - Walker (Box 21, Folder +)
    - Xenienkampf (Box 21, Folder +)
  - MISCELLANEOUS
    - Schiller. Works (Box 21, Folder ++)
    - Miscellaneous Illustrations - unidentified (Box 21, Folder +)
- Oversize, 30.02; (21 boxes) + 204 broadside folders
  Oversize is organized into six subseries: Boxes: Portraits, Boxes: Views, Boxes: Illustrations, Drawers: Portraits, Drawers: Views, and Drawers: Illustrations. The geographic names reflect names of countries and cities in the 1920's, at the time of the collection's creation.
  - BOXES: PORTRAITS
    - Imagines Nomine Illustrum ex Helvetia Virorum in Aes Incise ab Henr. P. Feninger, Pictore. Bound volume (Box 22, Folder +)
    - Portraits of Imminent German Characters. Bound volume (Box 22, Folder +)
    - "A"
      - Adelung, Johann Christoph, 1737-1806. (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Alfieri, Vittorio, 1749-1803. (Box 22, Folder +)
      - André, Johann, 1741-1799 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Anfossi, Pasquale, 1727-1797. (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Anna Amalie, duchess of Saxe-Weimar-Eisenach, 1739-1807 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Arnim, Bettina Brentano von, 1785-1859 (Box 22, Folder ++)
      - Arnim, Ludwig Achim, Freiherr von, 1781-1831 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Arndt, Ernst Moritz, 1759-1860 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - August Emil Leopold, duke of Saxe-Gotha-Altenburg (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Ayrer, Gottfried (Box 22, Folder +)
    - "B"
      - Baggesen, Jens Immanuel, 1764-1826 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Bahrdt, Karl Friedrich, 1741-1792 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Basedow, Johann Bernhard, 1723-1790 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Beauharnais, Eugène de, prince d'Eichstätt, 1781-1824 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Becker, Frau Christiane Louise Amalia Neumann, 1778-1897 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Beckmann, Johann, 1739-1811 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Beireis, Gottfried Christoph, 1730-1809 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Benda, Georg, ca. 1721-1799 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Bernhard Erich Freund, duke of Saxe-Meiningen, 1800-1882 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Bernhard Karl, duke of Saxe-Weimar-Eisenach, 1792-1862 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Bertuch, Friedrich Justin, 1747-1822 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Bethmann, Friederike Auguste Konradine Flittner Unzelmann, 1760-1815 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Bethmann, Simon Moritz von, 1768-1826 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Blessig, Johann Lorenz, 1747-1816 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Blumenbach, Johann Friedrich, 1752-1840 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Bode, Johann Joachim Christoph, 1730-1793 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Bodmer, Johann Jakob, 1698-1783 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Böhme, Johann Gottlob, 1717-1780 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Boettiger, Karl August, 1760-1835 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Bonnet, Charles, 1720-1793 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Bouterwek, Friedrich, 1766-1828 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Brandes, Johann Christian, 1735-1799 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Breitinger, Johann Jakob, 1701-1776 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Brentano, Clemens Maria, 1778-1842 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Brentano, Franz Dominico Maria Josef (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Brühl, Carl Friedrich Moritz Paul, 1772-1837 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Bruns, Paul Jakob, 1743-1814 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Buchholz, Wilhelm Heinrich Sebastian, 1734-1798 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Bürger, Gottfried August, 1747-1794 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Büttner, Christian Wilhelm, 1716-1801 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Burggrave, Johann Philipp, 1700-1775 (Box 22, Folder +)
      - Byron, George Gordon Noël Byron, 6th baron, 1788-1824 (Box 22, Folder +)
    - "C"
      - Cagliostro, Allessandro, conte di, assumed name of Guiseppe Balsamo, 1743-1795 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881 (Box 23, Folder ++++)
      - Carpzovius, Benedictus (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Carus, Karl Gustav, 1789-1869 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Casti, Giovanni Battisti, 1721-1803 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Chladny, Ernst Friedrich, 1756-1827 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Cimarosa, Domenico, 1749-1801 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Clodius, Christian August, 1738-1784 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Constant de Rebecque, Henri Benjamin, 1767-1830 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Cornelius, Peter Von, 1783-1867 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Cotta, Johann Friedrich von, 1764-1832 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Crell, Lorenz Florenz Friedrich von, 1744-1816 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Creuzer, Georg Friedrich, 1771-1858 (Box 23, Folder +)
    - "D"
      - Dalberg, Karl Theodor Anton Maria von, 1744-1817 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Dannecker, Johann Heinrich von, 1758-1841 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Daru, Pierre Antoine Noël Bruno, comte, 1767-1829 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - David d'Angers, Pierre Jean, 1788-1856 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Demmer, Friedrich (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Denon, Dominique Vivant, baron, 1747-1825 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - De Quincey, Thomas, 1785-1859 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Devrient, Frau Doris Böhler, 1805-1882 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Dietrich, Friedrich Gottlieb, 1768-1850 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Döbbelin, Karl Theopil, 1727-1793 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Döbereiner, Johann Wolfgang, 1780-1849 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - [Anna Charlotte] Dorothea, duchess of Kurland, 1761-1821 (Box 23, Folder +)
    - "E"
      - Eichhorn, Johann Gottfried, 1752-1827 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Ernst August, duke of Saxe-Weimar-Eisenach, 1688-1748 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Eschenburg, Johann Joachim, 1743-1820 (Box 23, Folder +)
    - "F"
      - Falk, Johannes, 1768-1826 (Box 23, Folder ++)
      - Fernow, Carl Ludwig, 1763-1808 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Fichte, Johann Gottlieb, 1762-1814 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Finucci, Mrs. Maddalena Riggi Volpato, 1765-1825 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Fischer, Kuno, 1824-1907 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Fichte, Johann Gottlieb, 1762-1814 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Foscolo, Ugo, 1778-1827 (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Franke, Heinrich Gottl (Box 23, Folder +)
      - Fresenius, Johann Philipp, 1705-1761 (Box 23, Folder +)